Manuela Sabatino

Email: mn.sabatino@gmail.com Web: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/mnsabatino & https://mn-sabatino.com

Tel: +44 (0) 7598 060934 **Address**: Walton-on-Thames, United Kingdom

Profile: Product Development Lead with almost 10 years of hands-on experience in geospatial analysis, database management and developing geospatial products. I am energized by challenges and problems. A wiz at analysing data and transforming it into useful information. I can work both on my own, using my own initiative and troubleshooting, and as part of a team. I enjoy learning new skills and technologies. I am currently looking for a new role in a multi-functional agile delivery team in which I can use my current skills supporting clients in extracting the highest value from the tools they have invested in.

Skills:

My Technical Skills

- Experienced of going through a full product lifecycle, integrating customer feedback into product requirements, driving prioritisation and pre/post-launch execution
- Experienced in agile development tools: Jira, ZenHub
- Version Control Systems: Github, BitBucket
- Experienced in analysing & updating PostgreSQL databases
- Experienced in Web GIS and the creation of web map
- Experienced in value-add analysis to business through use of data visualization software: Power BI, Google Data Studio
- Programming skills in Python, Javascript, SQL
- Language Proficiency: Italian(native), English(fluent),
 French(pre-intermediate)

My Soft Skills

- Great adaptability to learn new skills and technologies
- Ability to work under pressure, negotiate and resolve conflicts
- Ability to train others to use complex tools
- Ability to use creativity, reasoning, past experience, information and available resources to resolve issues
- Ability to work as part of a team, relate to people and manage conflict
- Respecting deadlines and working with others across the organisation to achieve a common goal
- Exemplary focus, ambition and attention to details

Work History:

Product Development Lead & Investor at MapStand Limited, London

March 2018 - present

MapStand is an exciting tech start-up building an open and real-time global activity map, providing geo-tagged news, data and location intelligence. Empowering individuals with knowledge of the energy and Geo-resource sectors.

- Working directly with the CEO to help to define and manage the products.
- Leading 5 cross-functional agile teams to deliver a multi-million-pound software solution, responsible for product design, strategy, roadmap, backlog, high-fidelity prototypes.
- Involved in the process of recruiting and hiring data analysts, developers and marketing agencies.
- Designed software, helped define high-level APIs and Architectures in AWS.
- Experienced in functional and behavioural testing.
- Designed and led the user research initiative, which helps to inform the product's core features and functionality.
- Providing value-add user analysis to business through use of data visualization software, Google Data Studio and Power BI.

Self Employed/ Technical Solution Consultant, London

October 2017 - March 2018

Providing consulting services and developing websites and platforms in Django, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, CMS (Wordpress, Drupal).

Building a disruptive SaaS solution to provide industry news, data and activity in a single accessible platform. The tech solution used is Geonode, Geoserver, Openlayers, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, Bootstrap.

GIS Analyst at Deloitte/WoodMac, London

<u>July 2014 – September 2017</u>

Following the Petroleum Services Group Departmental buy out from Deloitte, I joined Wood Mackenzie in March 2015.

- Working as part of an Agile/Sprint workflow team and responsible to design and develop workflows on database management and ETL process.
- Identifying and recommending GIS data quality and efficiency initiatives in the region to achieve ROI and business henefits
- Building relationships with key stakeholders within regional research and consulting teams to understand resource requirements and provide GIS support.
- Developing scripts and queries which streamline workflows and manage data in ArcGIS using Python, JavaScript and SQL.

Full Stack Web Developer at *Makers Academy*, London (Study Leave)

August - December 2016

16 weeks of Intensive Web development Bootcamp - Learning to code and become a software developer. Technologies and skills learned during the course:

Back-End learned during the course:

- Object oriented programming. Programming languages learnt: Ruby, Javascript, Python
- Rapid deployment with Heroku and Amazon AWS
- APIs such as Twilio, Facebook, Google Maps, JavascriptAPI
- Databases: PostgreSQL, ActiveRecord and Datamapper, MongoDB, Firebase
- Front-End technologies: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, Jekyll
- Frameworks: ExpressJS on NodeJS, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails, Django
- TDD: RSpec, Capybara, Cucumber, Jasmine, Mocha, Chai, Sinon
- Programming Practices: Pair Programming, Behaviour-Driven Development (BDD), Agile Methodologies, SOLID Design Principles, Version Control with Git and GitHub.

Spatial Coordinator at IHS Global Limited, Tetbury

July 2013 – July 2014

- Responsible for collating, reporting and presenting petroleum exploration and production information to stakeholders.
 using MapInfo and ArcGIS platforms
- Extracting and interpreting maps and illustrations from other formats
- Communicate with team members to ensure completeness and correctness of final products

3 positions as **CAD/ GIS Technician** at *Infotech Enterprises Europe Ltd,* Reading; *AGROS Realizzazioni S.r.l.*, Rome; *TERNA S.p.A.*, Rome May 2011 – July 2013

- QA/QC of digitising carried out to ensure it meets clients' requirement
- Providing accurate GIS data conversion and GIS analysis
- Georeferencing of data and maps to client approved datum and projection
- Photo-Interpretation of satellite imagery and aerial photography, including territorial database production and digital map creation for the Multinational Geospatial Co Production Program
- Experience of digitising, analysing, manipulating and presentation of complex geographical information on projects within the public and private sector
- Responsible for quality on GIS data and testing GIS applications
- Collection, post-processing and conversion of GPS data into GIS and CAD format
- 3D modelling of pylons and electrical stations and georeferencing using AutoCAD Map 3D
- Photomontages of 3D models using AutoCAD Map 3D and Photoshop CS5

Education:

- 2020 Product Manager Udacity Degree
- 2019 Agile & Scrum owner certification
- 2016 Web Development Bootcamp Makers Academy, London
- 2015 Fundamentals of SQL & Oracle Database 11g: Administration I course, London Met University
- 2013 Postgraduate Diploma in GIS, University of Ulster, Coleraine Campus
- 2012 Certificate in CAD Designer, Rome
- 2010 2:1 Bachelor's Degree in Natural Sciences, Biodiversity and Geo-Resources, Sapienza University of Rome

IT Skills

- Expert user of MapInfo Professional, ArcGIS 10.x, ArcGIS Pro, QGIS, OpenStreetMap tools, such JOSM and iD
- Expert user of UX tools to design/present wireframes and mockups: Figma, Adobe Design, Miro
- Knowledge in deploying/managing/monitoring services in AWS
- Knowledge in marketing/analysis tools/data visualisation: Hubspot, Google Analysis, Google data studio, Power Bi, CrazyEgg
- Database Developer: SQL Developer, PostgreSQL/PostGIS
- Proficient user in using Linux/Unix systems
- Agile development technologies: Trello, Zenhub, Jira
- Version Control systems: Bitbucket, GitHub

Interests:

I love Reading, especially Self-development readings. I love Hiking, Cycling, Ju-Jitsu, Qi-gong, Surfing. I am proud to say that I am volunteering at the Wave Project in Brighton, a surfing school that helps young people improve their emotional and physical well being. I am passionate about learning Blockchain, DeFi, NFTs and Cryptography.